Thor Lindberg

Home Reykjavík, Iceland

Email thor@lindberg.is

Website lindberg.is

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/thorlindberg

Coursera coursera.org/learner/lindberg

Profile

M.Sc. Design with a background in the intersection between medical science and information technology. I leverage this interdisciplinary perspective to act as a bridge between everyone from the client to the design team and development team. This is evident from my experience as an IT Consultant, as I lead the analysis and feature specification of projects with clients, and then collaborated with development teams to implement features in code for the final solution.

I invest my spare time in supplementing my education with courses, building software, exploring Iceland, and traveling in the U.S. to network with others in tech.

Education

IT University of Copenhagen 08/2020 — 06/2022

Master of Science in Digital Design

Thesis: Type-Extensible Objection Notation (TXON)

• Explorative design for typedJSON objects.

Relevant courses:

React Native mobile development with Expo.
 Advanced Design Processes. UX Design.

Copenhagen University 08/2017 — 07/2020

Bachelor of Science in Health Informatics

Thesis: Tools for caretakers of stroke victims

 Qualitative analysis to determine low-cost digital solutions for caretakers of stroke victims.

Relevant courses:

 Statistics. Mathematical Modelling. Programming for Biosciences. IT Security. Medical Image Analysis. Interaction Design.

Skills

Projects

Language English (fluent), Icelandic (beginner)

Figma Components/variants, flows, auto layout

Software JSX, TypeScript, Swift, SwiftUI, Git

Analysis Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Data Excel, Visual Basic for Applications

SharePoint, Azure, Office

Experience

Netcompany August 2022 — December 2023

IT Consultant

- Lead the analysis and initial design phase of multiple client projects and authored feature and design documents.
- Responsible for client contact, mediating meetings, status reporting, and managing the project timeline and tasks.
- Provided clients with digital transformation strategies through analysis of business processes and IT infrastructure.
- · Contributed to source code for Java-based backend.
- Contributed to code optimization and new features for a React Native and React Native for Web application.

National Special Crime Unit

October 2021 — July 2022

IT-Administrative Student

- Managed users of webportal and provided direct support.
- · Contributed to document processing architecture.
- · Authored documentation and website content.

IT University of Copenhagen

August 2021 — June 2022

Teaching Assistant

- · Assisted with teaching UX Design specialization.
- Assisted with assignments for courses in UX Design, Experimental Design, Python, and Javascript with MQTT.

Domino's Pizza

August 2021 — January 2022

Shift Leader

- Responsible for managing the store, closing the store, registering inventory, and matching store orders with use.
- · Delegated work to bakers and delivery drivers.
- · Primary pizza baker during rush hours.

Certificates

Mímir-simentun March 2024 — Now

Introduction to Icelandic (written and spoken)

University of California, San Diego March 2024 — Now

Data Structures and Algorithms Specialization

Courses: Test-driven algorithm design. Dynamic programming. Advanced algorithms and data structures. Pattern matching.

Meta March 2024 — Now

Front-End Developer Professional Certificate

Courses: JavaScript. Version control. HTML and CSS. Advanced React with components, hooks, APIs, and testing. UX/UI design.

Published

Áfangastaður - Explore Iceland apps.apple.com/app/id6466740299

iPhone app for exploring locations in Iceland, written in React Native and leveraging frameworks such as Redux Toolkit and React Context.